Register to The Harold Rome Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, 1939-1988; Series IV; .8' (2 boxes)
  - Personal Correspondence, IV.A
    - Osborn, Paul
      See: III.B. PRODUCTION MATERIALS, etc. Fanny, 76/23, p.
    - Pan American World Airways, ca. 1969 Sep. 9; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Parish, Betty Waldo, 1969 Jan. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Pearlman, Moishe, 1972-1973; 3 items (Box 80, Folder 11)
      Includes 2 typed letters signed (copies) from Rome
    - Plass, Margaret, ca. 1963?; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Players
      See: Drake, Alfred; and Lindsay, Howard
    - Plecy, Albert, 1968 May 2; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Porter, Cole, 1942 Sep. 10-15; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Pliner?, Sy, 1962 Jun. 18; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Record Division, 6 items (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Resnick, Regina, no year Mar. 9; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Rigby, Harry, 1956 Sep. 11-26; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Rittman, Trude, 1953 Jun. 25; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 12)
      See also: III.B. PRODUCTION MATERIALS, etc. Gone With the Wind - Japan, 77/26, p.
    - Robbins, Warren M., 1973 Mar. 17; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Rodgers, Richard, 1966-1978; 5 items (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Rosenberg, Jim, 1953 Nov. 9-13; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 12)
      Typed letter (copy) from Rome and typed letter signed from the National Conference of Christian & Jews, Inc.
    - Rubenstein, Arthur, 1961 Mar. 8; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Sainsbury, Robert, Sir, 1976 Oct. 28; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Salaway, Lowell, 1956-1957; 4 items (Box 80, Folder 13)
      2 typed letters signed (copies) from Rome
    - Samuels, Abram, 1977 Sep. 9; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Sawyer, Jeff, 1974 Jun. 17; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Scheftel, Stuart, 1958 Apr. 1; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Schein, Carol, 1969 Jan. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1982 Oct. 11; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Schore, Roger, 1976 Nov. 20; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Schubert, Bernard L., 2 items (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Schwartz, Arthur, 1976 Oct. 27; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Scott, Walter D., 1963 Nov. 13; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Segáll, Bernardo, no date; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Silber, Irwin, 1971 Mar. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Silverman, Rabbi Morris, 1960 Apr. 26; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Gary L., 1974 Mar. 4-11; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Southbury Training School, Inc. Home and School Association, 1975 Mar. 18; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Straus, Nathan, 1939 Jul. 27; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Strauss, G. L., no year Oct. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Summerell, Lynn, 1973 Mar. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Syracuse University. School of Art, 1964 Feb. 24; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Taylor, Deems
      See: American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers
    - Taylor, Harold, 1956 Apr. 17; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Tishman, Mrs. Paul, 1973 Mar. 12; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Twain, Norman, 1966 May 4; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - University of Pennsylvania. University Museum, 1975 Jan. 24; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - University of Tulsa
      See: Vunovich, Nancy
    - University of Wisconsin (Madison), 1962 Apr.-May; 5 items (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Vacha, John E., 1968 Mar. 2-17; 4 items (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Vlaminck, ?, ca. 1955 Apr. 26; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Vunovich, Nancy, 1978 Mar.-Apr; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - WNET/13, 1973 Apr. 13; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Waesche, Doris, 1956 Mar. 29; 3 items (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Weidman, Jerome, 1961 Jun.-Aug; 12 items (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Welch, Dorothy, 1973 Oct. 8; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Wiener, Bruce F., 1972 Nov. 3; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Winitt, Ben, 1963 Mar.-Nov; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Wise, Stephen S., 1946 Apr. 19; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Wolkenberg, Sidney L., 1959 Jul 10; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Wouk, Herman, 1962-1964; 4 items (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Yocum, J. H., 1962 Jul. 18; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Young, Frank M., 1978 Aug. 8; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Youngstein, Max E., 1955 Jan. 11; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1953-1983; 24 items (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Congratulatory Correspondence, IV.B
    - Destry Rides Again
      - Correspondence, 1959 Apr. 22-24; 133 items (Box 80, Folder 17-18)
        Includes 132 telegrams, some of which are from:
        Arlen, Harold
        Behrman, Sam
        Comden, Betty and Adolph Green
        DeMille, Agnes
        Douglas, Melvyn
        Engel, Lehman
        Furness, Betty
        Gershwin, Ira and Ruth
        Hart, Moss and Kitty
        Hayward, Leland
        Javits, Jacob
        Lane, Burton
        Merrick, David
        Rittman, Trude
        Robbins, Jerry
    - Fanny
      - Ashmead, Lawrence, 1986 Sep. 1; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Aslan, Benjamin, 1986 Aug. 18; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Keskinen, Mindy, 1986 Aug. 12; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Levin, Lynne Jaffee, 1956 Jun. 5; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Lippman, S.A., 1961 Jul. 10; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
        Clipping enclosed
      - Lipscomb, James E., 2 items (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Maule, Harry E., 1956 Jul 12; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - ?, "Joe", 1986 Aug. 17; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 19)
        Includes ALS from Beverly Sills
    - Gone With the Wind - Japan
      - Telegrams, 1969-1970; 13 items (Box 80, Folder 20)
        Including one from Richard Rodgers
      - Chodorov, Edla, ca. 1969 Dec; 3 items (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Chodorov, Jerome, 1969 Nov.-Dec; 3 items (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Engel, Lehman, 1969 Oct. 20; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Gershe, Leonard, 1969 Dec. 22; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Goetz, Ruth Goodman, 1969-1970; 4 items (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Grauer, Ben, [1969] Dec. 1; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Grauer, Melanie Kahane, [1969] Nov. 9-23; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Hart, Kitty Carlisle, 1969 Dec. 27; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Javits, Jacob K., 1969 Oct. 20; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Kober, Arthur, 1969-1970; 7 items (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Osborn, Millicent, 1969 Nov.-Dec; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Osborn, Paul, 1969 Dec. 25; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Parnis, Molly, 1969 Nov. 28; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Rodgers, Dorothy, 1969 Nov. 16; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Rome, Joshua, [1969]; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Rome, Rachel, 1969 Nov.-Dec; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Shumlin, Diane, 1969 Nov. 12; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Vidor, Doris, 1969 Nov. 24; 1 item (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Weidman, Jerome and Peggy, 1969-1970; 3 items (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Wood, Audrey, 1969 Oct. 29; 2 items (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Florence Rome's sister and mother, 1969 Nov.-Dec; 5 items (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Gone With the Wind - London
      - Telegrams and notes, 1972 Apr.-May; 54 items (Box 80, Folder 23-24)
        Including those from:
        Foote, Horton
        Kert, Larry
        Layton, Joe
        Rodgers, Richard
        Weidman, Jerome
    - Howe and Hummel
      - Krasny, Diana (Mrs. Milton), 1962 Jul. 22; 6 items (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - I Can Get It for You Wholesale
      - Telegrams, 1962 Feb.-Mar; 22 items (Box 81, Folder 25)
        Rome, Harold and Jerome Weidman
    - Wish You Were Here
      - Correspondence, 1953 Jan.-May; 3 items (Box 81, Folder 25)
        Klate, Charlotte
        Lastfogel, Abe
        Leinsdorf, Erich
    - Harold Rome (Marble Arch Gallery)
      - Telegrams and notes, 1964 Nov. 8-17; 25 items (Box 81, Folder 26)
        Crawford, Joan
        Lawrence, Steve and Eydie
        Sardi, Adelle and Vincent
        Lerner, Alan
  - Yale Correspondence, IV.C
    - Yale correspondence, 1954-1987; 22 items (Box 81, Folder 27)
      Includes letters from: Lieberson, Goddard and Wilson, Keith
      Also includes 5 typed letters signed (copies) from Rome
- Programs, 1938-1986; Series V; .8' (2 boxes)
  The programs are arranged alphabetically by show, then chronologically. Miscellaneous works and works of others are at the end.
  - Bless You All, 1950-1951; 6 items (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Call Me Mister, 1946-1947; 12 items (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Destry Rides Again, 1959-1978; 9 items (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Fanny, 1954-1986; 14 items (Box 82, Folder 4-5)
  - Gone With the Wind, 1972-1986; 19 items (Box 82, Folder 6-8)
  - La Grosse Valise, 1965 Nov.-Dec; 2 items (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - I Can Get It for You Wholesale, 1962 Feb.-Apr; 6 items (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Let Freedom Sing, 1942 Oct. 5; 1 item (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Little Dog Laughed, 1940 Aug. 20-31; 1 item (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Michael Todd's Peep Show, 1950 Aug. 7; 2 items (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Pins and Needles, 1938-1985; 17 items (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Pretty Penny, 1949 Jun.-Jul; 3 items (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Skirts, ca. 1944-1945; 1 item (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Star and Garter, 1942 Jul. 19; 1 item (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Stars and Gripes, 1943-1944; 2 items (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - That's the Ticket, 1948 Sep. 20; 1 item (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Wish You Were Here, 1953-1987; 9 items (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Zulu and the Zayda, 1965-1966; 4 items (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous performances, 1944-1982; 36 items (Box 83, Folder 21)
    Including armed forces shows
  - Works by others, 1954-1976; 30 items (Box 83, Folder 22)
- Art Works, Exhibit Catalogues, and Inventories, 1942-1977; Series VI; .4' (1 box)
  This series is divided into two subseries: A. Art Works by Harold Rome; and B. Exhibit Catalogues and Inventories. The art works fall into two categories: watercolors and oil paintings. An inventory of the oil paintings has been made, supplying a catalogue number, title, and date, if available. They are listed alphabetically by title with the untitled works at the end. The approximate dimensions (measured from the outside of the frame) are noted as well as whether they are signed. The exhibit catalogues and inventories are for Rome's art works as well as for his collection of African art, and are filed chronologically.
  - Art Works by Harold Rome, VI.A
    - Watercolors, ca. 36 items; 15" x 19"
      Not signed or dated
    - Oil paintings
      - Ancestor Assembly, 1964 Aug; 506
        41" x 51"
        Signed
        Title crossed off
      - Audience #2, 1967 Apr.-May; 260
        32" x 52"
      - Audience #4, no date; 262
        34" x 50"
      - Audience - 15, 1976; A-503
        33" x 50"
      - Audience Composition, 1962 Jun.-Dec; 217
        50" x 60"
      - Bar Mitzvah Boy, 1960 Dec; 234
        36" x 50"
      - Concert in Blue (#6), 1966 Jan.-Feb; 605
        35" x 50"
      - Critics, 1962 Nov; 312
        41" x 33"
      - Dance, 1962 Jan; 329
      - Dance to the Evening Star, 1965 Nov; 525
        33" x 51"
      - Don't Call Me I'll Call You I'm All Tied Up Now, 1960 Sep; 197
      - A Dream of Horses, 1961 Jul; 261
        "Destry Rides Again" on label on side of frame
      - Half-forgotten Teddy Bear #2, 1964 Jan; 442
      - Hommage to Moiseyev, 1961 Jul; 264
      - King of the Bushongo #3, 1964; 507
        32" x 51"
      - A Kwele Ace, 1975; 310
        34" x 51"
      - Life Story, 1960 Oct; 227
        32" x 50"
      - Mother and Child #5, 1963; 522
        40" x 53"
      - My Long Ago, 1964 Jul; 765a
        44" x 56"
        Also noted: 2612 Marble Arch
      - A Night at the Opera, 1976 summer; 276
      - A Pink Staff?, no date
        37" x 50"
      - Portrait of Fritz Loewe, 1962; 405
        34" x 42"
      - The Saints Look Down, 1967; 606
      - Shake Hands, 1960 Oct.-Dec; 229
      - Song No. 2, 1959 Sep
      - Stop Waltzing Around in My Mind, 1963; 3435
        40" x 54"
      - Tempo Diablo, 1960 Jun; 127
        36" x 51"
      - Tennessee Albee, 1961 Sep; 268
      - Three Graces, 1964 Feb; 428
      - Variety, 1960 Sep; 194
      - Where Roses Bloom, 1962 Nov; 311
      - Which Way is Home #2, 1964 May-Jun; 504
        32" x 49"
      - The Wolf that Swallowed Red Riding Hood #31, 1964 Jul; 501
      - You Can Take Me Out of Burlesque, but You Can't Take the Burlesque Out of Me, 1960 Sep; 195
      - No title (portrait of an old woman), 1960
      - No title, 1975
      - No title, 1977
      - No title, no date
      - No title, no date
  - Exhibit Catalogues and Inventories, VI.B
    - Catalogues of Rome's paintings and of his African art collection, 1942-1971; 12 items (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Inventories/price lists of Rome's paintings, 1959-1965; 6 items (Box 84, Folder 1)
- Clippings, 1873-1986; Series VII; 1.7' (4 boxes)
  The clippings are divided into two subseries: A. Stage Works; and B. Miscellaneous Articles. Subseries A is arranged alphabetically by work, then chronologically. Subseries B contains clippings grouped by various subjects which are then filed chronologically.
  The clippings have been copied onto acid-free paper. Many of the clippings were originally found in disassembled scrapbooks.
  - Stage Works, VII.A
    - Alive and Kicking, 1949-1950; 15 items (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Bless You All, 1950-1951; 72 items (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Cabaret Tac, no date; 1 item (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Call Me Mister, 1946-1949; 237 items (Box 85, Folder 4-7)
    - Destry Rides Again, 1958-1982; 177 items (Box 85, Folder 8-9)
    - Fanny, 1952-1986; 414 items (Box 86, Folder 10-15)
    - Gone With the Wind, 1968-1978; 225 items (Box 86, Folder 16-19)
      Includes copy of scrapbook of Dallas performance
    - La Grosse Valise, 1965 Nov. 16-17; 3 items (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Howe and Hummel, 1873-1902; 5 items (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - I Can Get It for You Wholesale, 1961-1970; 87 items (Box 87, Folder 22-23)
    - I Hear America Singing, 1940 Oct. 1; 1 item (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Let Freedom Sing, 1938-1942; 15 items (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Little Dog Laughed, 1940 Aug; 16 items (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - Lunchtime Follies, 1943 Jan. 9; 1 item (Box 87, Folder 26)
    - Michael Todd's Peep Show, 1950 Jun; 9 items (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - Pins and Needles, 1938-1988; 183 items (Box 87, Folder 28-30)
    - Pretty Penny, 1949 Jun. 21; 1 item (Box 87, Folder 31)
    - Sing Out the News, 1938-1939; 42 items (Box 87, Folder 32)
    - Skirts, 1945 May; 1 item (Box 87, Folder 33)
    - Star and Garter, no date; 1 item (Box 87, Folder 34)
    - Stars and Gripes, 1943 Jul.-Aug; 28 items (Box 87, Folder 35)
    - That's the Ticket, 1948 Sep. 15-29; 6 items (Box 87, Folder 36)
    - Wish You Were Here, 1950-1957; 137 items (Box 88, Folder 37-38)
    - Zulu and the Zayda, 1965-1966; 57 items (Box 88, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, VII.B
    - Articles and reviews of performances of miscellaneous musical works by Rome, 1939-1978; 87 items (Box 88, Folder 40-41)
    - Marble Arch Gallery show and recording, 1964-1965; 26 items (Box 88, Folder 42)
    - Fidelity-Philadelphia Trust exhibit of Rome's work, 1966 Jun. 7-12; 10 items (Box 88, Folder 43)
    - African art collection, 1958-1978; 16 items (Box 88, Folder 44)
    - Biographical articles, 1938-1977; 16 items (Box 88, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1943-1978; 34 items (Box 88, Folder 46)
- Photographs, 1928-1986; Series VIII; 2.9' (7 boxes)
  This series includes photographs, negatives, and slides of: A. Harold Rome, alone and with others; B. Harold Rome's Stage Works; and C. Harold Rome's Art Works. The first subseries includes photographs of Harold Rome and others arranged chronologically. Series B comprises photographs of or relating to Rome's stage works. These are listed by show, then chronologically, with miscellaneous photographs at the end. Subseries C is grouped by subject with miscellaneous photographs at the end. The photographs are arranged chronologically within these groups.
  Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively, with oversize items in boxes 96 and 97 as well as in an oversize folder (5ov).
  - Harold Rome and Others, VIII.A
    - Rome with dance band in New Haven, 1928; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome, his first year at Yale School of Architecture, 1930; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome with Ed Murrow and Mike Fish, 1940; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome with others, at a film screening, 1943; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
      Including J. Rosamund Johnson
    - Portrait by Carl Van Vechten, 1950; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome with Eddie Fisher, 1952; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome with Mary Martin, 1952; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome with Mary Martin and Josh Logan, 1952; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome in Rome with Marta Loren?, Nardo Bercovici, Jack and Marion Javits, and Peg Stewart, 1953; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Mary Martin, and Joshua Logan and family at Mary Martin's house in CT - singing Peter Pan score, 1954; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Harold and Florence Rome with Frederick Lowe and friend at Cannes, 1958; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified photos, 10 items (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Rome in front of his portrait of daughter, Rachel, 1958; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome in hallway with "all of his paintings", 1962; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome with Arthur Schwartz and Joe Kipness at Jule Styne's birthday party, 1962; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome with Zero Mostel, Burton Lane, Kate Mostel, and Jule Styne, at Styne's birthday party, 1971; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome with paintings of playing cards and African sculpture, 1974; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome at ASCAP party at Sardi's celebrating publication of Thou Swell, Thou Witty, on life and lyrics of Lorenz Hart, with Gerlad Marks and Stanley Adams, 1976 Sep. 15; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Correspondents Club of Japan party?, 1977 Jun.?; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome receiving the Richard Rodgers ASCAP award from Hal David and Dorothy (Mrs. Richard) Rodgers, 1977 Jun.?; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified photos, 1962-1974; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Rome at ASCAP reception with Charles Strouse, Stanley Walden, E.Y. "Yip" Harburg, Stanley Adams, and Bob Austin, no date; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Rome with Lehman Engel, no date; 2 items (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Rome with Mr. and Mrs. Richard Rodgers and Mr. Zin Arthur, no date; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Wish You Were Here display at Doubleday Book Store, no date; 2 items (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Rome with Harold Arlen, Arthur Schwartz, and others, no date; 1 item (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified photos, no date; 9 items (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified portraits of Rome, no date; 3 items (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Harold and Florence Rome with many others, 1942 Feb. 26; 1 item (Folder 5ov)
      Group photo of the Third Annual Dinner of the Overseas Press Club of America at the Waldorf Astoria, New York City
    - Rome with a model for an advertisement?, no date; 1 item (Folder 5ov)
  - Stage Works, VIII.B
    - Bless You All, 1950; 4 items (Box 89, Folder 6)
      Includes 2 slides
    - Call Me Mister, ca. 1946-1947; 4 items (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Destry Rides Again, 1959; 34 items (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Fanny, ca. 1954-1986; 26 items (Box 89, Folder 9-10)
      Includes 9 slides and a negative
    - Gone With the Wind - Japan, 1969-1970; 94 items (Box 89, Folder 11-12)
    - Gone With the Wind - Japan, 1969-1970; 36 items (Box 96)
      Slides
    - Gone With the Wind - London, 1972-1973; 8 items (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Gone With the Wind - Los Angeles, 1973; 24 items (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Gone With the Wind - Houston, 1978 Jul; 85 items (Box 96)
    - Gone With the Wind - Dallas, no date; 65 items (Box 89, Folder 15-17)
      Includes 44 slides
    - I Can Get It for You Wholesale, 1962; 2 items (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Little Dog Laughed, ca. 1940 Jul. 13; 1 item (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Pins and Needles, 1938-1978; 12 items (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Romanoff and Juliet, ca. 1957 Oct. 10; 2 items (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Sing Out the News, 1939; 1 item (Box 90, Folder 22)
      Slide
    - Star and Garter, 1939; 1 item (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - Stars and Gripes, ca. 1943 Jun. 23; 16 items (Box 90, Folder 24)
      Includes 2 negatives
    - Streets of Paris, ca. 1939 Jun. 19; 2 items (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Wish You Were Here, 1951; 5 items (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - Yale band concert, 1959; 2 items (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous photos, no date; 7 items (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - Art Works, VIII.C
    - Marble Arch Gallery, ca. 1964-1965; 8 items (Box 90, Folder 29)
    - Fidelity-Philadelphia Trust, 1966; 3 items (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - "Early paintings - photos taken by Life photographers", no date; 11 items (Box 90, Folder 31)
      Color negatives
    - Miscellaneous paintings, no date; 99 items (Box 90, Folder 32-36)
      Includes 78 photos and 21 color negatives
    - Miscellaneous paintings, no date; 293 items (Box 96–97)
      Three carousel trays and two boxes of slides
- Miscellaneous Items, 1938-1988; Series IX; .8' (2 boxes)
  The items in this series are grouped by subject, then chronologically, with a miscellaneous section at the end. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series with oversized items housed in an oversize folder (9ov).
  - Biographical articles, lists of published music and records, inventory of personal library, and interviews, 1961-1988; 40 items (Box 91, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles, eulogy, and toast by Rome, 1951-1954; 10 items (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Army memorabilia, 1943-1946; 7 items (Box 91, Folder 4)
    Including correspondence, citation, dependency benefit card, separation record, and certificate of honorable discharge
  - Contracts, agreements, and correspondence regarding leases and insurance, 1949-1956; 6 items (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Certificates and awards, 1949-1965; 4 items (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Writings by others
    - Pins and Needles: when social significance came to Broadway, 1977 Aug. 18; Goldman, Harry Merton; 1 item (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - The Scarlett Letters, c1971; Rome, Florence; 1 item (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Theater memorabilia
    - Call Me Mister, 1946; 1 item (Folder 9ov)
      Watercolor sketch for "Overture Drop" signed by Lester Polokov
    - 4 complementary house seat tickets for Fanny and a That's the Ticket sticker, 5 items (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Poster for the Goodspeed Opera production of Fanny, 1986; 1 item (Folder 9ov)
    - Gone with the Wind poster from Japanese production, 1969; 1 item (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Gone with the Wind model of riverboat for the Japanese production, 1969 Dec. 3; 1 item (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Gone with the Wind, 1970; 1 item (Box 92, Folder 13)
      Watercolor sketch Scene Act I Tara with inscription: For Harold and Florence with love David
    - Miscellaneous items, 1938-1987; 31 items (Box 92, Folder 14)
      Including receipts, first day cover envelopes, brochures, and lists
- Sound Recordings, Series X
  Sound recordings have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information about archival recordings relating to Harold Rome, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.